
Function: mount(ReactComponentOrElementOrMarkupString, rootElement, functionCallback(ReactObject))

Description: Inserts a React component within a target element in the DOM.

Returns: React Component Object, or $A object if chained.

Note: If a markup string or DOM node is mounted, it will automatically be converted to a React component object, which will remove any attached events if present. Event listeners can be applied to the newly rendered content within the callback function.

Example:

// Mount a React component within a DOM element
var myReactComponentObject = $A.mount(ReactComponentObject, domElement);

// Insert a DOM element within another element targetted with a CSS selector after converting it to a React component.
var myReactComponentObject = $A.mount(domElement, "#myTargetNodeId");

// Insert a markup string element within another DOM element after converting it to a React component.
var myReactComponentObject = $A.mount('<div>Here we are now, entertain us.</div>', domElement);

// Insert a React component within a DOM element and exicute a callback when done
var myReactComponentObject = $A.mount(ReactComponentObject, domElementToTarget, function(ReactObject) {
  // Do something after the mounting is complete.
});

// Or the same using chaining

// Mount a React component within a DOM element
var myChain = $A(domElement).mount(ReactComponentObject);

// Insert a DOM element within another element targetted with a CSS selector after converting it to a React component.
var myChain = $A("#myTargetNodeId").mount(domElement);

// Insert a markup string element within another DOM element after converting it to a React component.
var myChain = $A(domElement).mount('<div>Here we are now, entertain us.</div>');

// Insert a React component within a DOM element and exicute a callback when done
var myChain = $A(domElementToTarget).mount(ReactComponentObject, function(ReactObject) {
  // Do something after the mounting is complete.
});

// To return the modified element within a chain, use the "return()" method.

var myReactComponentObject = myChain.return();
