
Function: $A(stringOrObjectID)

Description: Return the registered DC object bound to a specific string or object ID.

Returns: DC Object.

Note: ID refers to the matching DC.id property value of a registered DC object. The ID of a DC object must always be unique, and may consist of a string, domElement, or other object type. However, a React component object cannot be used as the ID of a DC object. After a DC object is returned, only valid properties and methods specified in the DC API are available on that object. If the string or object ID passed to $A() is not bound to a DC object, then the argument will automatically be parsed and returned as a Chain object instead.

Example:

// Get the registered DC object with DC.id = "myDCObjectID"
var DC = $A("myDCObjectID");

// Get the registered DC object where DC.id is set to a DOM element.
var DC = $A(domElement);

// To return the DC object bound with a React component object, the getDC() function must be used instead.

var DC = $A(ReactComponentObject).getDC();
