
DC.getOffset(boolForceReturnAbsolutePositioning, boolForceReturnRelativePositioning, boolOnlyReturnTopLeft)

Description: Returns the rendered offset values of DC.outerNode.

Returns: Object with properties: "left", "top", "right", "bottom", "height", and "width"

Note: When only the first parameter is set, the returned offset values automatically reflect positioning information that is valid for the 'position' property value for that element. When boolForceReturnAbsolutePositioning or boolForceReturnRelativePositioning is set to true, the returned offset will instead compute the designated position regardless what the 'position' property is set to. When boolOnlyReturnTopLeft is set to true, a modified object is returned that only includes two properties, "left" and "top". The DC.getOffset() function always returns an offset object, even when chained.

Example:

var offsetObj = DC.getOffset();
