
Function: toNode(stringMarkup, boolOnlyReturnNode)

Description: Converts a markup string into a DOM fragment or element node.

Returns: domFragment, domElement, or $A object if chained.

Note: The toNode() function will return a document fragment by default, which may include multiple elements at the same logical level. However, when boolOnlyReturnNode is set to true, a standard DOM node will be returned instead. When this occurs, only the first top level container element is returned, and all others at the same logical level are ignored. The returned DOM node may contain any number of additional elements though, with no restriction.

Example:

// Create a document fragment with multiple elements at the same level.
var myElement = $A.toNode('<i>This is a test.</i><br /><i>So, try to look impressed.</i><br /><i>Hey, that rhymed!</i>');

// Create a DOM element and return the first DOM node only. (<i...</i>)
var myElement = $A.toNode('<i>This is a test.</i><br /><i>So, try to look impressed.</i><br /><i>Hey, that rhymed!</i>', true);

// Or the same using chaining

// Create a document fragment with multiple elements at the same level.
var myChain = $A('<i>This is a test.</i><br /><i>So, try to look impressed.</i><br /><i>Hey, that rhymed!</i>');

// Create a DOM element and return the first DOM node only. (<i...</i>)
var myChain = $A('<i>This is a test.</i><br /><i>So, try to look impressed.</i><br /><i>Hey, that rhymed!</i>').toNode(true);

// To return the modified element within a chain, use the "return()" method.

var myElement = myChain.return();
