AccDC 4X Installation

Installing AccDC 4X for use within other projects is relatively simple.

1. Copy the folder named "AccDC" and paste this within the src folder of your React project. All that is needed is Core/API.js, however the other files provide access to advanced customizable widgets that can be imported and configured for use within any project. (More of these will be added in the future.)

2. Install the background process dependencies used by AccDC for use within your project. You can do this by copying the file named "InstallDependencies.bat" into the root folder of your React project, then click the file to run it, or run it from a command prompt.

3. Then import the core AccDC API into your project, which will instantiate the $A API for use within any React component.

import $A from "./AccDC/Core/API";

To access $A from any external React component file, simply create a reference to the same object.

let $A = window.AccDC;

All $A API properties and methods will then be available using this object.