
Function: destroy(objectDCOrID, boolKeepInternalContent)

Description: Destroys a DC object generated by AccDC.

Returns: Boolean: True if successful, false otherwise.

Note: If boolKeepInternalContent is false or undefined, or if the DC object is closed, destroy will clean and remove all internally stored DOM nodes associated with the DC object. If boolKeepInternalContent is true and the DC object remains open, all displayed content within the DC object will be preserved at its current location in the DOM before the associated DC object is destroyed.

Example:

// Destroy the DC object, including all associated content.
$A.destroy(objectDCOrID);

// Destroy the DC object, but preserve all associated content in the DOM beforehand.
$A.destroy(objectDCOrID, true);

// Or the same using chaining

// Destroy the DC object, including all associated content.
$A(objectDCOrID).destroy();

// Destroy the DC object, but preserve all associated content in the DOM beforehand.
$A(objectDCOrID).destroy(true);
