
Function: find(stringID, functionCallback(DC))

Description: Searches through all registered DC objects and performs a callback function on each match.

Returns: DC Objects Array.

Note: When dcID is set to "*", all registered DC objects will be sent to the callback. If dcID is set to any other string value, any substring ID match will be sent to the callback. Multiple ID strings to be used in searching must be separated with a comma (","). Alternatively, dcID may be set to a function to perform a custom search using more advanced criteria. The find() function does not support chaining.

Example:

// Search through all registered DC objects and perform a callback on each DC object.
$A.find("*", function(DC) {
  // Do something with DC
});

// Search through all registered DC objects that include "TestIDName" within DC.id and perform a callback on each matching DC object.
$A.find("TestIDName", function(DC) {
  // Do something with DC
});

// Search through all registered DC objects that include "TestIDName1" and "TestIDName2" within DC.id and perform a callback on each matching DC object.
$A.find("TestIDName1,TestIDName2", function(DC) {
  // Do something with DC
});

// Search through all registered DC objects using a custom filter and perform a callback on each matching DC object.
$A.find(function(ID) {
  // ID is the DC.id property value to check for matches against.
  // Return true to pass DC to the callback, or false to skip.
},
function(DC) {
  // Do something with DC when passed to the callback.
});
