
Function: getDC(stringIdOrObjectOrReactComponent)

Description: Return the registered DC object bound to a specific string ID or object.

Returns: DC Object.

Note: ID refers to the matching DC.id property value of a registered DC object. The ID of a DC object must always be unique. Since getDC() is a default function for $A, the syntax $A(stringOrObjectID) will perform the same action as $A.getDC(stringOrObjectID). However, to prevent processing conflicts, the syntax $A(ReactComponentObject) will not get the bound DC object, but will instead pass the React component object into the $A object for standard chaining. After a DC object is returned, only valid properties and methods specified in the DC API are available on that object.

Example:

// Get the registered DC object with DC.id = "myDCObjectID"
var DC = $A.getDC("myDCObjectID");

// Get the registered DC object where DC.id is set to a DOM element.
var DC = $A.getDC(domElement);

// Or the same using chaining

// Get the registered DC object with DC.id = "myDCObjectID"
var DC = $A("myDCObjectID");

// Get the registered DC object where DC.id is set to a DOM element.
var DC = $A(domElement);

// Get the registered DC object bound to a React component
var DC = $A.getDC(ReactComponentObject);

// Or the same using chaining

// Get the registered DC object bound to a React component
var DC = $A(ReactComponentObject).getDC();

Special Cases:

When a DC object is bound to a React component, the DC object can be accessed from within the lifecycle methods for that object using this.props.DC.

The following invokes the DC.unmount method for closing a DC object from within a React component JS declaration.

handleFormSubmit(ev) {
  // Do something.
  this.props.DC.unmount();
}

// Equally, the following invokes the $A.unmount method on a React component, which automatically recognizes when a DC object is already bound to that object.
$A(ReactComponentObject).unmount();

// The same is true for all of the other $A methods that are available for dynamic processing, such as $A.mount and $A.mountWithin.

// Mount a DC object within another root element using the ReactComponentObject as reference.
$A(ReactComponentObject).mountWithin(domElement);
