
Array Property: lastCreated

Description: An array of all of the most recently registered DC objects as passed to $A() for instantiation.

Returns: DC Objects Array.

Note: Whenever $A() is invoked to instantiate a new set of DC objects, lastCreated will always be overwritten with a new array. The lastCreated array does not support chaining.

Example:

var lC = $A.lastCreated;

alert(lC.length);

// Variable 'id' equals DC.id for the first registered DC object in the set.
var id = lC[0].id;
