
Function: mergeGlobal()

Description: Retroactively merges newly declared global DC properties and methods into all registered DC objects.

Returns: Null.

Note: Merging only applies to previously instantiated DC objects. All properties and methods that have the same name will be overwritten with the new global properties and methods as declared within setGlobal(). The mergeGlobal() function does not support chaining.

Example:

$A.mergeGlobal();
