
Function: announce(stringOrElementNode, boolDoNotRepeat, boolIsAlert)

Description: Performs an unobtrusive announcement for screen reader users using a string message or the textual contents of a DOM element.

Returns: String, domElement, or $A object if chained.

Note: Designed to function automatically within screen readers that properly support ARIA live regions. The announce method is also prototyped to the String object for alternative usage. Method supports auto-queuing for rapid succession such as within live chat applications.

Example:

// Basic announcement of textual content within a DOM element.
var myElement = $A.announce(domElement);

// Announce a string message while suppressing repeat text
var myString = $A.announce(stringMessage, true);

// Announce a string message while suppressing repeat text, and invoke a system wide alert message no matter which application has focus
var myString = $A.announce(stringMessage, true, true);

// Using strings

// Basic announcement of a string object
"Downloading, please wait.".announce();

// Announce a string object while suppressing repeat text
stringMessage.announce(true);

// Announce a string object while suppressing repeat text, and invoke a system wide alert message no matter which application has focus
stringMessage.announce(true, true);

// Or the same using chaining

// Basic announcement of textual content within a DOM element.
var myChain = $A(domElement).announce();

// Announce a string message while suppressing repeat text
var myChain = $A(stringMessage).announce(true);

// Announce a string message while suppressing repeat text, and invoke a system wide alert message no matter which application has focus
var myChain = $A(stringMessage).announce(true, true);

// To return the modified object within a chain, use the "return()" method.

var myObject = myChain.return();
