
Function: focus(domElement)

Description: Forces progrommatic focus to any element.

Returns: domElement, or $A object if chained.

Note: This method moves programmatic focus, and does not explicitly set or trigger any attached focus handlers.

Example:

// Move focus to a DOM element
$A.focus(domElement);

// Or the same using chaining

// Move focus to the first heading element on the page
var myChain = $A("h1").focus();

// To return the modified object within a chain, use the "return()" method.

var myObject = myChain.return();
